This is a great "who dun it" guessing game and you should use a minimum of 6-8 people.
The more the merrier.
What you do one, is choose one person who is just going to run the game.
They don't actually get to participate, so if you are playing this with kids maybe if you have an adult in the room they could choose to be the one running the game or just maybe an adult that doesn't feel like playing if its a group of adults they can run the game.
Basically, they are going to have all the adults close their eyes or kids close or cover your eyes and the person running the game will choose one person to be the murderer.
They just choose them by tapping them gently on the head.
That person is the murderer only they know it and the person running the game knows it.
Everybody's eyes open and the game begins.
You just start walking around the room shaking everybody's hands with a nice greeting "hi, how are you", "hi, how are you".
When the murderer chooses they will choose a victim and kill them.
How they will do that is by shaking their hand and doing a little tickle inside.
So just scratching the inside of the hand but doing it very discreetly so that no one else sees when the victim has been killed.
They have to shake three more hands just so that it's not obvious who killed them and then they get to choose a way they want to die nice, and big, and dramatic.
So if I was to kill David "hi, how are you", he's going to shake three more hands and on the third hand die.
"Aahh", good, then we have our victim dead lying on the floor and the rest of us have to try to figure out who killed him.
Now again only the person running the game and the person that's dead knows, but the person that's dead can't say anything.
So you vote and the majority wins so whoever you want to, its kind of a witch hunt at this point, you just pick and choose who you think might look suspicious and if that person actually is indeed the murderer lets say you say "ah", everyone agrees it was Joe, the person running the game knows if its Joe or not if it was Joe they say "yes, you guys have won", if its not they just say "nope, that is not the murderer", and you just, Joe has to die though and then the games goes again and again until either the murderer is killed every body off without being killed themselves or until they've been found out by the crowd.
And that's how you play murderer.